<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="layout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<content>

<h1>Object Network Interface</h1>

<p class="intro">ONI is a distributed object and remote procedure
call system implemented using YAML on top of TCP/IP or HTTP.</p>

<p>YAML is quite suitable for the serialization of objects
required by remote object access protocols. The simplicity of
the protocal makes short work of setup and is one of the primary
benefits that ONI has over other systes such as SOAP and XML-RPC.</p>

<p>ONI only works with Ruby, but it should be easy enough to 
generalize to other languages that support YAML. It is also
very alpha, but nonetheless it has been put to work
under more realistic conditions and it looks promising.</p>


<h1>News</h1>

<h3 class="date">2008-02-22</h3>

<h2>Initial Release</h2>

<p>ONI has sitting around my harddirve for years now, comllecting digital dust.
When I first put it together I was hevily into learning YAML and it seemed 
like one fo the natural places to put YAML to good use. However, YAML has yet
to really catch fire, JSON seems to have stolen most of it's glory. And though
YAML is fairly popular among RUby circles, Ruby already has <code>drb</code>,
so it's not like there was a pressing need for a YAML based alternative. So
ONI never matured past the initial prototype implementation.
</p>

<p>REgardless I recently decided that it was foolish not to at least "put it out there".
Perhaps someone else will come across it and have the inspiration to take it to 
the next production ready level.</p>


<h1>Installation</h1>

<p>Via RubyGems:</p>

<pre><code>
  $ gem install oni
</code></pre>

<p>With the source code:</p>

<pre><code>
  $ tar -xzf oni-x.y.z.tar.gz
  $ cd oni-x.y.z
  $ ruby setup.rb
</code></pre>

<p>Linux/Unix users might need to use <code>sudo ruby setup.rb</code>.</p>


<h1>Usage</h1>

<p>For detailed usage documentation, please refer to the <a href="rdoc/index.html">RDocs</a>.</p>


<h1>Development</h1>

<p>ONI is hosted by Rubyforge at <a href="http://rubyforge.org/projects/oni">http://rubyforge.org/projects/oni</a>.</p>

<h2>Anonymous Subversion Access</h2>

<p>This project's SVN repository can be checked out through anonymous access with the following command(s).</p>

<pre>
  svn checkout svn://rubyforge.org/var/svn/proutils/oni
  svn checkout http://proutils.rubyforge.org/svn/oni
</pre>

<h2>Developer Subversion Access via SSH</h2>

<p>Only project developers can access the SVN tree via this method. SSH must be installed on your client machine. Substitute developername with the proper values. Enter your site password when prompted.</p>

<pre>
  svn checkout svn+ssh://developername@rubyforge.org/var/svn/proutils/oni
</pre>


<h1>Special Thanks</h1>

<p>Big thanks goes to the Three Yamlos, of course: Oren, Clark, and Igny.</p>


<h1>License</h1>

<p>ONI, Copyright &#x00A9; 2008 <a href="http://proutils.tigerops.org">Tiger Ops</a></p>

<p>This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the MIT or Ruby License.</p>

<p>This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.</p>

</content>

